A Guide to the Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters Records, 1905
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters Records 1905
Special Collections, Kegley Library
2002.3
11 folders..
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Gary and Ann Laing in February 2002.
Custodial History
Records found by donors Gary and Ann Laing in the attic rafters of the Hillenberg store in Crockett, Virginia.
Scope and Content
The Republican Party of Wythe County generated these lists of eligible voters in 1905 in order to plan campaign strategy and target voters. The lists are typed on carbon paper and provide name of voter, age, political party affiliation, and occupation. Names are arranged alphabetically. While all of the lists only list white male voters, most also include names of black voters. Lists of black voters eppear at the of each list.
Many of the lists exhibit severe water and vermin damage; condition is noted for each list in the Contents List.
Contents List
- Folder 1. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Austinville Precinct. 1905., 4 p.
  This list is incomplete and in poor condition. Includes list of black voters.
- Folder 2. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Boyd's Precinct. 1905., 9 p.
  This list is incomplete and in very poor condition.
- Folder 3. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Crockett Precinct. 1905., 6 p.
  This list is in poor condition. Includes list of Republicans not registered and instructions for registering new voters. "There is said to be at least fifteen young men to be registered at your precinct, who would vote the Republican ticket. It is only in getting the young men registered that we can have any chance to carry the county since the Treasurers Office disenfranchised so many many of our people."
- Folder 4. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Foster Falls Precinct. 1905., 5 p.
  This list is in poor condition. Includes list of Republicans to be registered.
- Folder 5. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Grahams Forge Precinct. 1905., 5 p.
  This list is in poor condition. Includes list of black voters.
- Folder 6. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Henley's Precinct. 1905., 5 p.
- Folder 7. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Max Meadows Precinct. 1905., 9 p.
- Folder 8. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Patterson Precinct. 1905., 9 p.
  This list is in fair condition. Includes list of black voters and Republicans to be registered. Also includes instructions for registering voters. "Keep on hunting till you register 35 young Republicans to administer a rebuke to the Democrats who disenfranchised so many honest citizens."
- Folder 9. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Peppers Ferry Precinct. 1905., 8 p.
  This list is in fair condition. Includes list of black voters.
- Folder 10. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Pine Ridge Precinct. 1905., 7 p.
  This folder is in fair condition. Includes list of black voters and a list of Republicans to be registered. Also includes instructions for registered voters. "Wytheville is UNGODLY. Republicans are not as plentifull [sic] as they ought to be, but it is a missionary field. Hunt up the young men."
- Folder 11. Wythe County Republican Party List of Voters. Porter's Crossroads Precinct. 1905., 1905
  This list is in good condition. Includes list of black voters.